Elizaveta Shcherbakova

Moscow, Russia +79151065891 liza.shch.98@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Telegram

Summary

Enthusiastic Senior Frontend React developer with 4+ years of experience in developing and supporting products with 10M DAU, designing new features for high-loaded services and releasing them into production. Strong communication skills reached by working in Agile feature teams.

Skills

Hard: TypeScript, JavaScript, React, Redux, MobX, SASS, CSS, HTML, Webpack, Rollup, SSR, WebdriverIO, Jest, Jenkins, CI/CD, ESlint, REST API, Axios, Git, Gitlab, Github, Grafana, Jira, Sentry, Confluence, Proxyman

Soft: Task management, communication, problem solving, conflict resolution, flexibility, attention to details, multitasking, product-oriented

Work Experience

VK (ex. Mail.Ru Group), Moscow, Russia

Frontend developer

September 2021 - Present

- Feature lead of a single limited Mail and Cloud space storage with paid subscriptions support (React + TypeScript), which brought 150% of whole department quarter planned revenue (2M DAU).
- Designed architecture of space-clearing feature, designed API, developed Frontend, built SLO graphs in Grafana with alerts support.
- Developed Metathreads configuration settings in Mail (grouping letters by category), enabled on 100% users.
- Created a native emoji picker for letter edit window with a stable fallback to images for old operation systems and browsers.
- Wrote 300+ e2e tests using WebdriverIO to check stable service work.
- Integrated internal UX design system into Cloud project.
- Managed intern growth and made onboarding, interviewing new developers.

Mail.Ru Group, Moscow, Russia

Junior Frontend developer

October 2019 - September 2021

- Redesigned Payment platform using React (300k DAU).
- Improved payment banners (taxes, bills etc.) by developing universal structure with configuration on backend (70k payments per month).
- Fixed a problem of disabling third-party cookies in **iframes**. In result the Payment platform was stabilised on production **in 2 days**.
- Developed letter reading UI using Marusia's Voice Assistant (100k DAU).
- Designed a library for generating content from Notion pages with custom components for our designers' needs.

Autel LLC, Moscow, Russia

Intern

March 2019 - October 2019

• Developed MVP of system for storage public notification facilities

Education

Bauman Moscow State Technical University, 2015-2021 Master of Computer science and engineering